米高梅电影公司出品
菲律宾浴血战
主　要　演  员
Robert Montgomery　罗伯特·蒙哥马利
John Wayne　约翰·韦恩
本片基于约翰·布尔克利和罗伯特·凯利的真实
英雄事迹改编，影片细致描画了菲律宾保卫战
中美国鱼雷快艇在41年12月到42年4月间的战斗.
中尉巴尔克利因此被授予荣誉奖章。
威廉·怀特将此故事写成了小说，
而编剧弗兰克·威德将之改编成了剧本，
影片曾获第18届奥斯卡录音、特技效果奖提名。
珍珠港事件发生不久,日军进攻菲律宾.
驻菲律宾的美军某鱼雷快艇中队不得不
与占绝对优势的日本舰队展开苦战。
本片清楚体现了艇员的决心和勇气。
兹向为本片拍摄作出巨大帮助的美国海军,
美国陆军,美国海岸警卫队以及战略规划处
(注:CIA的前身)致以最诚挚的谢意.
"今天,所有的枪炮停止了吼叫.人类史上
巨大的悲剧终于结束.我们终于迎来了
伟大的胜利...                                    .
这是那千万名为了今日的胜利而捐躯,
长眠于菲律宾的丛林中及静卧于太平洋
深处的将士们的心声."                        .
麦克 阿瑟 将军
菲律宾马尼拉湾    1941年
各艇注意!各艇注意!
All boats from Brick.
保持队形.他们还都没见过鱼雷快艇呢.
Make them look good. It's the first time they've seen PT boats.
各艇注意!
All boats from Brick.
各艇注意!继续保持队形.
All boats from Brick. Nice going.
布里克,我是拉斯悌.
Brick from Rusty.
是时候表演一下了.
That ought to show them.
他们开的真棒,长官.
They maneuver beautifully, sir.
-真是一群意气风发的小伙子. -谢谢,长官.
- A splendid-looking lot of men. - Thank you, sir.
先生们,我们迟到了.
Gentlemen, we're late.
你们的鱼雷艇开的真的很棒.
Those boats of yours maneuver beautifully.
不过这玩意用来打仗恐怕还是单薄了点.
But in wartime, I'm afraid I prefer something more substantial.
估计很难会有人相信...
It's wonderful the way people believe...
呃,你们的那些火力强大的舢板.
...in those high-powered canoes of yours.
拉斯悌,难道你不相信它们吗?
Don't you believe in them, Rusty?
我还信你那些什么 "我可以亲自指挥.."的废话呢.
And I let you sell me that stuff about a "command of my own. "
你指挥34号艇呢,不是吗?
You skipper the 34 boat, don't you?
我还指挥过浴缸里的肥皂呢!
I used to skipper a cake of soap in a bathtub too.
检阅完毕.
Secure from inspection.
解散!
Dismissed!
-你们今天表现真不错. -谢谢.
- Nice show today, fellas. - Thank you.
上尉?
Lieutenant?
晚上好.
Good evening.
认识一下,鱼雷艇艇长 索悌·隆格, 拉弗悌·艾肯....
I'd like you to meet some boat skippers. Shorty Long, Lefty Aiken...
嘿,别走啊?
What the-?
我来介绍,安迪·安德鲁斯. 他刚来这报到.这是索悌·隆格.
I want you to meet Andy Andrews. He just reported. Shorty Long.
-很高兴认识你. -谢谢.
- Happy to know you. - Thank you.
这是拉弗悌·艾肯.
Lefty Aiken.
拉斯悌在哪?
Where's Rusty?
大概在准备报告吧.
Looks like he's doing his paperwork.
-安迪! -嗨,拉斯悌.
- Andy! - Hello, Rusty.
拉弗悌说你刚报到,怎么样?
Lefty said you'd checked in. What'll it be?
啤酒.
Beer.
你在算所得税吗?
Figuring your income tax?
当然不是.我一定要想出充足的理由
No. I had to work out a smooth line...
说服舰队司令让我去驱逐舰.
...to convince the admiral I belong on a destroyer.
就是说你是真的不想在这呆了?
So you're really quitting the squadron?
开这种木头玩意可没前途.
Can't build a Navy reputation riding a plywood dream.
你是怎么想的? 是打算为自己出名...
What are you aiming at? Building a reputation...
还是...为团队想想?
...or playing for the team?
嘿,布里克,这么多年,你给了不少慈父般的建议.
Look, Brick, for years I've been taking your fatherly advice.
但从来没有什么好主意.
It's never been very good.
从现在起,我要独立了.
From here on in, I'm a one-man band!
那好,我会把你的申请向上呈交的.
Send in your request. I'll forward it.
来杯啤酒?
How about a beer, Rusty?
5杯生力啤酒.
Five San Miguels.
这音乐不错.
Nice music.
哦,三宝颜的猴子没有尾巴
Oh the monkeys have No tails in Zamboanga
Oh the monkeys have no tails
它们的尾巴被鲸咬掉了.
They were bitten off by whales
哦,三宝颜的猴子没有尾巴
Oh the monkeys have No tails in Zamboanga
哦他再也不会回苏比克湾了
Oh he won't go back to Subic anymore
哦,我们要升起帆去追赶她
Oh we'll hoist the jib and spank her
我们齐声喊"一二,起锚!"
And we'll pipe, "All hands, up anchor!"
但是它再也不会回苏比克湾了.
But he won't go back to Subic anymore
幸运儿!
Lucky dog!
[small beer: 也指小人物]
淡啤酒,淡啤酒,很淡的啤酒.
Small beer! Small beer! Very small beer!
牛奶!沙士汽水!沙士汽水!
Milk! Sarsaparilla! Sarsaparilla!
姜汁汽水!
Ginger ale!
油漆以及红辣椒!
Paint varnish and dash of red peppers!
先生们!
Gentlemen!
请肃静!
I want absolute silence.
这两位有话说.
Boats here has a little speech to make.
我可不是来发表演讲的,
I'm not going to make a speech.
只说点事.
Just got something to say.
明天我们的老朋友- 我们的军医就要离开我们了.
Tomorrow our old pal Doc here is going out.
在海军干了30年,他退休了.
He's being paid off after 30 years.
你们中的很多人可能在弄明白 在海军中呆30年意味着什么之前,
I know most of you kids got a ways to go before you find out...
就已经离开了海军.我告诉你们,
...what 30 years in the Navy means.
那是奉献!
It means service.
30年来,经历了战争与和平年代的
Tough and good.
艰苦的奉献.
It means serving your country in peace and in war.
让我们举杯...
So let's raise-
现在广播重要声明
We interrupt this program for an important announcement.
今天早晨,珍珠港平静的周末被雷电打破..
This morning, the Sunday calm of Pearl Harbor was broken by the thunder-
在这个时刻让我们一起举杯
So let's raise our glasses and drink to Doc...
向受人尊敬的医生
...with all the solemnity that this occasion demands.
致敬.
To Doc.
抱歉打断大家
Sorry to have to interrupt you.
女士们先生们
Ladies and gentlemen.
我要宣布一个重要的声明
I have a very important announcement to make.
官方的正式声明.
This is official.
小日本今晨袭击了珍珠港.
The Japanese have attacked Pearl Harbor.
目前我们就知道这么多.
There are no details.
全体陆海军人员立即前往驻地报到.
All Army and Navy personnel must report to their posts immediately.
重复一遍:
I repeat:
全体陆海军人员立即前往驻地报到.
All Army and Navy personnel must report to their posts immediately.
拉斯悌,走吧.
Let's go, Rusty.
喂,你落了东西了.
Didn't you forget something?
这片土地,我父亲长眠与此,
Land where my fathers died
这片土地,朝圣者的骄傲,
Land of the pilgrims' pride
在山间的每个角落
From every mountainside
让自由之声响遍.
Let freedom ring
请等一下.
Hold it.
我什么也不知道.我只是按命令办.
I don't know. I'm just doing what I'm told. You know.
惠特尼,有什么小道消息吗?
Any hot dope, Whitey?
什么也没有,布里克.
Nothing yet, Brick.
那里可能是日本人要进攻的地方.
That's probably where they'll attack.
请继续.
Carry on.
我们会竭尽全力的,长官.
We'll do our best, sir.
刚收到的,长官.
This just came in, sir.
先生们,
Gentlemen.
你们可能已猜到...
You may assume that a state of war exists between...
合众国与日本已经处于交战状态.
...the United States and the Empire of Japan.
大家要保持见机行事.
Govern yourselves accordingly.
拜托了,各位.
My compliments, gentlemen.
这是命令.
Here are the orders.
喂,霍里.
Hooley.
我们有任务吗?
Got anything for us?
你是那个部分的?
What do you call that outfit again?
鱼雷艇3中队.
Motor Torpedo Boat Squadron Three.
还没有呢.或许明天就有了.
No orders for you now. Maybe tomorrow.
你想让我们怎么办,坐着傻等吗?
What do you want us to do? Sit on our duffs?
我去问下老头子,你等会.
I'll ask the old man. Stand by.
派一艘艇巡逻,另派一艘待命.
Have one boat patrol the bay and one stand by for messenger duty.
全部快艇已加油完毕. 鱼雷在半小时内完成装填.
All boats fueled. Torpedoes will be loaded within a half-hour.
有什么消息?
Any dope?
要我们待命.
Our orders are to stand by.
那些驱逐舰可没闲着.
Those destroyers aren't standing by.
他们象比赛似的沉在航道上.
They went down that channel like a rat race.
可能是有命令要他们那么做吧.
Somebody might have given them orders to go.
给你发了20艇12.7mm机枪.
You got 20 boxes of 50-caliber there.
##给拉弗悌 12艇.
Give 12 to Lefty.
请注意:
Now hear this.
不明飞机正接近甲米地.
Unidentified aircraft approaches Cavite.
Unidentified aircraft approaching Cavite.
是日本人的.
Those are Jap planes.
朝这来了.
Headed this way.
所有鱼雷艇立即出港.
All boats out in the bay.
跟我来,等待信号.
Follow me, and stand by for signals.
是演习吗?
Is that another drill?
不是演习.
Can't be a drill.
我们加入海军,天天就是训练,训练.
All we get in this Navy is drill, drill, drill.
紧急出动.
Fire in the paint locker!
敌机成一字队形.
One formation.
敌机散开了.
Breaking off.
朝我们来了,长官.
Heading up our way, sir.
准备散开.
Stand by to disperse.
各艇注意, 各艇注意.
All boats from 41. All boats from 41.
准备散开.
Stand by for scatter plan.
装备散开.
斯莫基,
Thank them, Smokey.
按B方案散开.
Scatter plan Baker.
散开!
Execute.
Execute!
干得漂亮,斯莫基.
Good shooting, Smokey. Recognize him?
打的就是他.
Iknew him well. Shaved his father.
小伙子,干掉他.
Get him, Junior!
各艇注意.
All boats from 41.
返回基地.
Return to base.
很坚固吧？
Pretty rugged, isn't it?
我们走吧,拉斯悌.
Let's go, Rusty.
长官,我们都检查过了.仓库被摧毁了.
We've checked everything, sir. The storeroom's gone.
鱼雷没有了,发动机没有了; 备件没有了,什么都没有了.
No torpedoes, no motors, no spare parts, no nothing.
不知道科雷吉多尔岛那有没有鱼雷.
Wonder if they have any torpedoes at Corregidor.
- 对啊. - 我去找找看.
- Might be. - I'll check on it.
嗨.
Hi.
有点糟吧.
A little rugged.
怎么你衣服湿了吗?
You got wet clothes on underneath that blanket?
不,长官.只是有点害怕.
Just scared.
是啊,你还没学会克服它.
You haven't got a monopoly on that.
你在看什么,厨师?
What are you looking at?
我想看看亚利桑那号驶进港的情景...
Just looking for the Arizona to come steaming up to base...
那光亮闪闪的380毫米大炮...
...with her 14-inch guns blazing...
海军舰艇里最好的厨房.
...and the best cook stoves in the Navy.
亚利桑那号?
Arizona?
亚利桑那号.
Arizona.
陆军的人说一支日本特遣舰队正朝林加延湾驶来.
Some Army boys told us a Jap task force is headed for Lingayen Gulf.
- 侦察机在黄昏时发现的. - 肯定是要登陆.
- Planes spotted it at sunset. - Must be another landing.
林加延湾
Lingayen?
医生,给我剪刀.
Give me those scissors, Doc.
-离这只有约200英里.
That's only about 200 miles from here.
是235英里.
Two thirty-five.
干嘛不把他们干到海底去?
Why don't we knock those babies off?
怎么打?就凭几条鱼雷艇吗? 把铅笔给我.
What with? A cake of soap and a bathtub? Give me that pencil.
布里克雷先生,舰队司令要你立刻去见他.
Mr. Brickley, the admiral, sir. Right away.
检查一下油料.
Check your gasoline.
怎么样,心情是不是好点了?
Feel better?
你来指挥.
Take over.
动起来吧,检查舰艇, 准备出海.
Line up your engines, check all boats. Step on it, men.
大家出动.
Fire in the paint locker.
-长官? -布里克雷.
- Yes? - Brickley.
长官,布里克雷来了.
Mr. Brickley, sir.
- 长官,你找我?
You sent for me?
呃,你准备一艘船把我的参谋部 转移到科雷吉多尔岛去.
Yes, get a boat ready to move my staff to Corregidor.
你的任务是在马尼拉和岛之间传送讯息.
You'll run messenger trips between Manila and The Rock.
去和参谋长安排一下.
Work out a schedule with the Chief of Staff.
甲米地基地已经失陷了.
Cavite is finished as a base.
把你的部队转移到巴丹的西西曼湾湾.
Move your outfit to Sisiman Cove on Bataan.
就这么些吗,长官.
Is that all, sir?
就这些.
That's all.
听说一只日军特遣舰队正朝 林加延湾驶来,是真的吗?
Is it true that a Jap task force is moving into Lingayen Gulf, sir?
把它发送出去吧.
Type that and send it.
布里克雷,你过来坐.
Sit down, Brickley.
特遣舰队将会登陆.
That task force will land.
你我都无法阻止的.
You and I can't stop it.
如同西班牙的无敌舰队的遭遇, 珍珠港的袭击是场巨大的灾难,
Pearl Harbor was a disaster, like the Spanish Armada.
听我说,孩子...
Listen, son...
...比如,我们是职业运动员.
...you and I are professionals.
如果老板说"牺牲", 我们就来个牺牲触击...
If the manager says, "Sacrifice," we lay down a bunt...
...让别人去跑出全垒打吧.
...and let somebody else hit the home runs.
我们都知道那些退役了的驱逐舰
We know about those destroyers...
都停在圣地亚哥港.
...out of commission, tied up around San Diego.
我们本可以在这用上他们...
We could use them here...
但他们不在这儿...
...but they're not around.
他们也不会在这了...
They won't be.
现在就是我们为国捐躯的时刻了..
Our job is to lay down that sacrifice.
我们长久以来训练为的就是这个..
That's what we were trained for.
这是我们的职责.
That's what we'll do.
明白吗?
Understand?
谢谢.
Thank you.
长官,都准备好了.
All set, sir.
不出动了.
Secure your boats.
不出动了?
Secure the boats?
索悌,你把将军和他的参谋送到岛上去.
Shorty, take the admiral and his staff to Corregidor.
拉弗悌,你每天早上9点传送讯息.
Lefty, you stand by to run a messenger trip daily at 900.
其他人,把艇带到西斯曼湾去.
The rest of you take your boats to Sisiman Cove.
- 你和我们呆在这. - 是,长官.
You join us there.
布里克,你不是开玩笑吧?
Are you kidding, Brick?
没有什么理由,他们只需要去..
Theirs not to reason why, theirs but to do-
去死.
And die.
我可不想当烦死人的信差.
I don't want to be bored to death running messages.
我以为你会有兴趣的.
I'll see that you get the more intriguing ones.
- 你这样有用吗? - 当然有.
Does that help?
有吃的吗,布里克?
Any chow, Brick?
- 刀片和牙膏. - 真是上好的食物.
- Razor blades and toothpaste. - That's a swell diet.
- 头,有什么消息吗? - 日军运输船在北边登陆了.
- What's the dope, Skipper? - Jap transports landed up north.
他们正修理巴丹呢.
They're giving Bataan the works.
- 早上好,长官.有消息吗? - 没有.
- Good morning, sir. Any dope? - No dope.
早上好,长官.
Good morning, sir.
刚收到的消息.
A message just came in.
布莱克 威尔将军要立刻见你. 十万火急.
And Admiral Blackwell wishes to see you immediately. Very urgent.
谢谢.
Thank you.
或许是要我们去给加西亚送信.
Probably wants us to carry a message to Garcia.
克洛斯,在41号艇待命.
Cross, stand by with that 41 boat.
我们先去试试刀片.
Let's use those razor blades.
喂,厨子,我要你保证清洁的卫生环境.
Chief, I want you to keep sanitary precautions at all times.
在那边挖个大洞,盛放垃圾或其他什么玩意.
Dig a big hole over there to put the garbage in and what-have-you.
把这些锅碗瓢盆都洗干净.
Ik eep these pots and pans scrubbed.
不管干什么,不要把任何东西扔到Cove湾里.
Don't put anything in the bay, whatever you do.
见鬼,这就是你煮出来的汤吗?
Holy smokes, cook! You call that soup?
不,长官,那是洗碗水.
No, sir, that's dishwater.
准尉...
Ensigns.
我想你们已经厌烦了...
I suppose you're getting tired...
来回送信及日常的巡逻.
...of all this routine messenger and patrol duty.
我知道你们一定很想找机会 证明你们关于鱼雷快艇的理论.
I know you're anxious to prove your theory of the motor torpedo boat.
你们也知道...
As you know...
日本人夺取了苏比克湾.
...the Japs have Subic Bay.
他们在巴朗牙堡垒调了艘巡洋舰, 轰击我们在巴丹的阵地.
They've got a cruiser at Fort Balanga shelling our positions on Bataan.
我们要么击沉它,
We've either got to sink her...
要么就只能撤退.
...or pull out our troops.
科雷吉多尔, 西西曼湾,苏比克.
Corregidor, Sisiman Cove, Subic.
这是战线.
The lines are here.
日本人在这布设了水雷.
The Jap minefields here.
他们的巡洋舰...
Their cruiser...
在这儿...
...there.
去击沉它.
Sink her.
对不起,长官.借我用用.
Excuse me, sir, may I borrow that?
我想一艘艇就行,你呢,莱恩?
I think one boat, don't you, Mr. Ryan?
不,布里克雷,我想需要两艘.
No, I think two boats, Mr. Brickley.
我们去两条艇,长官.
Two boats, sir.
黄昏出发.
Shove off at dusk.
晚安.
Good evening, gentlemen.
我们没那么多钢盔,
We haven't got enough steel helmets to go around...
所以只给你们枪炮手和鱼雷操作员配发钢盔.
...so issue them to your gunners and torpedo men.
我再重复一遍..
I repeat again...
不要使用无线电,除非你肯定 确实已经被日本人发现了
...do not open up on your radios until you're sure they've spotted you.
如果被发现,用12.7mm机枪打灭探照灯.
Use your 50-calibers to knock out the searchlights.
你说派两艘艇去,另一艘派谁去?
You said there'd be two boats. Who's the second?
34号艇,拉斯悌.
Rusty with the 34 boat.
好了,我们18:00出发.
That's all. We'll shove off about 1800.
我来算下航速..
I'll regulate the speed...
我们要在天黑时到达这里.
...so we'll reach the end of this leg here in darkness.
好的,安迪.
All right, Andy.
好,我们走,马汉.
All right, let's go, Mahan.
-长官.. - 嗯?
Sir.
没什么...
Nothing.
-长官? -没门,索悌,
- Sir? - Not a chance, Shorty.
抄一份送给安迪,他在34号艇.
Copy that in longhand and give it to Andy on the 34 boat.
积极的家伙.
Eager beavers.
这是怎么回事?我的艇是最好的艇.
What's the matter with us? We have the best boat.
我的是最快的艇.
And my boat's the fastest one in the water.
17:30
Seventeen-thirty.
医生,你来看下我的手指...
Doc, will you take a look at this finger?
小伙子..
Fellas...
我们最终获准..
...we finally got the green light...
去击沉苏比克湾里的一艘日本巡洋舰.
...to sink a Jap cruiser in Subic Bay.
我们要穿过这片日本人的水雷区和炮火覆盖区, 后面是他们的巡逻艇.
Through those Jap mines, artillery and past them patrol boats.
我们肯定有一艘能回来.
One of our boats ought to get back.
你们如果不准时就赶不上了.
Any of you guys not on time don't get to go.
好了,莎士比亚.
All right, Shakespeare.
肘部血液毒,你应该去医院.
You got blood poison to the elbow. You belong in the hospital.
我回来就去医院.
When I get back.
- 如果你还想要胳膊,就得现在去医院. - 涂点碘酒,包扎一下.
- If you don't want to lose it, go now. - Put iodine on it and wrap it up.
拜托了,医生.替我保密.
Look, Doc, do me a favor. Ik eep your mouth shut about it.
别忘了在蛋糕上撒点盐.
Don't forget to put a pinch of salt in that pancake batter.
我床铺下面有果酱,拿给他们.
You'll find jam under my bunk. Give them that.
都准备好了,拉斯悌.
All set, Rusty.
- 你的胳膊没事吧? - 没事.
- Your arm all right? - Sure.
准备完毕.
Everything's ready.
好了,施拉格,放松一下吧.
Okay, Slug, relax until time to shove off.
嘿,拉斯悌!
Hey, Rusty!
让我看看你的胳膊.
Let me see that arm.
你应该去医务室,伙计.
You're going to sick bay, fella.
布里克,你不是怕我抢你的功吧?
You aren't afraid of a little competition, are you, Brick?
索悌,34号艇不去了, 改派31号艇,让他们做好准备.
Shorty, the 31 boat'll go instead of the 34. Get her ready.
我可不想失去一个优秀的副手.
I won't lose a good exec because you're out of your head.
把船停好.
Secure the boat.
喂,莫加西!
Mulcahey!
我会教训你的.
For two bits, I'd punch you right in the mush.
- 你知道原因. - 知道.
- You know the score. - Right.
让你的鱼雷操作员待命.
And have your torpedo man stand by in case those circuits fail.
起锚.
Wind them up.
快!
Come on.
我们走.
Let's go, Good Luck.
护士!护士!
Corpsman! Corpsman!
嚷嚷什么?这是医院.
This is a hospital. Why don't you hire a hall?
把帽子摘了.
Take off your hat.
只是手指被割伤了,我没有...
It's just a little cut along the finger. I don't-
衬衫到那有点难脱.
Shirts are hard to get out here.
假臂也是.
So are artificial arms.
海军的.
Anchors aweigh.
你发烧了,43度.
You've got a temperature a little over 103.
吃了这些药片.
Chew these sulfur pills.
- 那是弹片? - 是的.
What is this, shrapnel?
怎么受的伤?
Where did you get it?
在甲米地湾.
Cavite.
没伤到.
It doesn't hurt.
没受伤??
It doesn't hurt?
你没听过血液毒吗?
Did you ever hear of blood poisoning?
如果你再晚来几小时, 就必须截肢了.
If you'd been a few hours later, I'd have had to take that arm off.
指挥部通知说伤员2小时后到.
Headquarters called. Casualties arriving in two hours.
-有多少伤员? -200多.
- How many? - Over 200.
那得快点.赶紧休息一下.
Double deckers. Try and get some rest.
有的忙了.那个年轻人病了.
We've got work to do. That young man is sick.
给他降降温,想办法让他睡着.
Get his temperature down and get him to sleep.
然后休息一下.
Take a few minutes yourself.
你发烧了,最好躺下.
You'd better lie down. You have a temperature of 103.
我知道.
So I've heard.
你们海军总是比正常人高两度.
You Navy boys always run about two degrees above normal.
你是什么军衔?
Must be the time spent at sea.
你什么军衔?
What is your rank?
陆军少尉.
Second lieutenant.
而我是海军中尉,所以请注意你的言语.
I'm a j. g., so watch your language.
喔,我还以为你是骑警呢.
I thought you were a motorcycle cop.
虽然你官阶高,不过这轮不上你发话.
Despite your gold braid, you don't tell us.
乖乖躺下吧.
We tell you. So lie down.
脱裤子.
Unfasten your pants.
-你说什么? -我说,脱裤子.
- What? - Unfasten your pants.
-脱裤子.
Unfasten your pants.
往右一点.
Come right a little.
靠右.
Right a little!
长官,现在应该到雷区了.
This should be the minefields now, sir.
往左一点.
Left a little.
靠左.
Left easy.
稳住.
Steady as she goes.
-隆格 的艇上有信号吗? -长官,看不见他.
- Any sign of Long's boat? - Don't see him, sir.
-出什么毛病了? -汽油里面有石蜡.
- What's wrong? - This gas was loaded with wax.
发动机罢工了.
Sabotage.
-要多久能修好? -大约要40分钟.
- How long to get started? - About 40 minutes.
尽量快点.
Hurry it all you can.
得花40分钟修理.
Forty-minute job.
他们想俘虏我们.
They're trying to pick us up.
打掉那盏灯!
Get that light!
弃船!
Abandon ship!
31号艇被击中了,长官.
The shore batteries got the 31 boat, sir.
鱼雷准备.
Stand by your torpedo tubes.
预--备
Stand by!
一号发射!
Fire one!
二号发射!
Fire two!
-唔,厨子,我们成功了. -什么成功了?
- Well, Cookie, we did it. - Did what?
去哪了?
Been someplace?
我们把小日本的巡洋舰炸沉了.
We blew that Jap cruiser into next month.
哦,是吗?
Recently?
吃东西了吗?
Pick up any chow?
米克,我忘了告诉你了, 你的衣服泡胀了,.
I forgot to tell you, Mick, your laundry's drying. Came out swell.
你们还错过了一顿丰盛的早餐.
You guys were late for breakfast too. It was wonderful.
对,葡萄的水果蛋糕.
Yeah, cupcakes with raisins.
听着,你这大嘴巴.
Listen, bigmouth.
那可是个大家伙,配有232mm大炮...
That ship was a big, converted job with eight-inch guns...
而我们把它炸上了天.
...and we blew her into kingdom come.
是汤普金斯.
Tompkins.
-怎么会这样? -他是机枪手.
- How? - Machine gun in the belly.
我们还失去了31号艇.
Yes, and we lost the 31 boat too.
我们部队昨晚在巴丹给日本人来了一击.
Our club on Bataan took another rap on the chin last night.
你们海军去哪了?
Where is that Navy of yours, anyway?
在纽约中央公园小湖里吗?
On Central Park Lake?
那会很孤独的.
They'll be along.
我要到圣诞节才能再见到他们.
We won't see them till Christmas.
我想,那时候,我们的空军已经打赢了这场战争了.
By then the Air Force will have won the war, I suppose.
问题是空军在哪儿呢?
Only, where is the Air Force?
敌机来袭.
Enemy aircraft approaching.
关闭所有通风机和隔仓.
Secure all ventilators and bulkheads.
重复一遍:敌机来袭.
Repeat: Enemy aircraft approaching.
关闭所有..
Secure all...
通风机和隔仓.
...ventilators and bulkheads.
身边有那样女孩真好...
That's a nice kind of a girl to have around...
在战争时期...
...in wartime.
任何时候.
Or anytime.
她...
She's...
那样可爱.
...kind of cute too.
大家都这么认为的.
11,000 guys can't be wrong.
很辛苦吧.呃?
Pretty tough, huh?
你们这些小姑娘为什么不歇会?
Why don't you girls get some rest?
你以为我们不想吗?
Don't think we won't.
考虑一下?
How about it?
你要去问问那个又高又黑的讨厌鬼吗?
Going to ask tall, dark and obnoxious?
晚上要跳舞呢,去弄漂亮一点.
Got to look pretty for that dance tonight.
胳膊怎样了?
How's the arm?
没事.
Okay.
是吗.去跳舞吗?
Good. Would you like to go to a dance?
不,我不跳舞的.
Listen, sister, I don't dance.
现在也不想去学跳舞.
And I can't take time out now to learn.
我只想离开这儿.
All I want to do is get out of here.
你等一等.
Now, wait a minute before you start popping off.
我可不在乎她们怎么样.
I don't care if they dance their dogs off.
讲点道理吧.她们也需要放松一下.
Be reasonable. Those girls need relaxation.
需要做点什么提醒她们..
Something to remind them they're...
她们是女人.
...women!
没错.
Sure.
可没人提醒我我是什么.
They're not going to remind me of anything.
不过是一个...
All uglied up in those...
丑陋的乡巴佬..
...potato bags.
-你好. -你好.
- Hello. - Hello.
很棒的舞会.
Nice party.
既然来了,不妨多呆一会吧.
Now that you're here, why don't you stay a while?
哦,不了.我来这是为了..
Oh, no, I just came over to...
谢谢你...
...thank you for...
呃,谢谢你帮我补好了衬衫.
...you know, sewing up my shirt.
但你根本就会跳舞,对吗?
But you do dance, don't you?
晚上好,莱恩先生.
Good evening, Mr. Ryan.
你好.
Hello.
你不觉得把胳膊放回吊床上更好吗?
Think you better put that arm back in the sling?
说不定什么时候你要用它.
You might use it someday...
犁地,剪裁纸娃娃.
...for plowing, or cutting out paper dolls.
为什么这么在意?
Why the eager interest?
职业习惯?
Professional?
感觉象回到家一样,对吗?
It's rather like back home, isn't it?
门廊,
The porch...
吊床,
...hammock...
萤火虫..
...fireflies.
你家在哪?
Where?
衣阿华州.
Iowa.
你知道,高大的玉米林.
You know, tall corn.
你呢?
Where?
上纽约州.
Upper New York State.
你知道
You know...
苹果.
...apples.
那些炮的火光
Those gun flashes...
看起来就象萤火虫一般.
...look like fireflies.
每个夜晚,
Every night...
它们越来越近.
...they come a little closer.
嗨,拉斯悌.
Hi, Rusty.
桑蒂,这是布里克雷上尉.
Sandy, this is Lt. Brickley.
- 迪邬斯小姐. - 你好.
- Miss Davyss. - How do you do?
-你好.
Hello.
舞会不错吧?
Nice party?
非常棒.
Swell!
舞跳得怎样呢?-
That big lug dance?
好极了.
Wonderful.
我只踩到她一次.
Only stepped on her foot once.
什么事?
What's up?
等会再说好了.
It can wait.
你们谈好了.
Go ahead.
安迪很利索就把巡洋舰干掉了.
Andy did a pretty good job on the cruiser.
剩下的只有加德纳...
All we've got left is Gardner.
哦,他还太那么年轻..
He's such a young kid for-
这任务要求心灵手巧.
It's tricky duty.
为什么不呢?
Why not?
好吧.
Okay.
他的手有多糟?
Just how bad is that hand?
手指一直裂到骨头,感染还没好.-
The finger is open to the bone. And there's still infection there.
我们找医生谈谈去.
Let's go talk to the doctor.
我的指头是不是正在好转?
Is it healing?
是的.
Yes.
快点,布里克,帮我把帽子戴上.
Come on, Brick. Help me pour the heat on.
情况怎么样？
How'd it go?
有人阵亡吗?
Did you lose anyone?
没有,长官.
No, sir.
莱恩先生把我们都救上来了.
Mr. Ryan picked us up beautifully.
对不起,长官.
I'm sorry, sir.
我宁愿失去的是自己的胳膊而不是33号艇.
I'd rather lose my right arm than the 33 boat.
别那样想.
Couldn't be helped.
会成功的.
Paid off.
是,长官.
Yes, sir.
谢谢.-
Thanks.
安迪被7.7mm枪弹打穿了脚踝.
Andy got a 7.7 through both ankles.
哎,斯奈克.
Snake.
你接替安迪指挥34号艇.
Take Andy's place on the 34 boat.
是,长官.
Aye, aye, sir.
运气有点背啊,安迪.
That's tough luck, Andy.
伤口好点吗?
How're they feeling now?
一点也不好.
They don't.
需要什么尽管说.
You give us the word if you need anything.
尽管说.
Sure.
我们会去看你的.
We'll be over to see you.
等你好了再回来指挥.
The job's yours again when you can take it.
我下周...
I'll give you the nudge...
就回来.
...about next week.
收缆.
Wind them up.
你从未见过那场面. 我们把小日本炸沉了!
You never saw nothing like it. We blew that Nip out of the water!
-两条鱼雷,正中要害. -是这样的,米克.
- Two fish, right in the guts. - Get this, Mick.
我们开始是这样...
We started to run like this-
早餐是杯形蛋糕.
We had cupcakes for breakfast!
加葡萄干.
With raisins.
- 欢迎来做客,迪邬斯小姐. -谢谢.晚上好.
- Glad to see you aboard, Miss Davyss. - Thank you. Good evening.
先生们,我来介绍...
Gentlemen, I would like to present...
莱恩先生的客人,迪邬斯小姐.
...Mr. Ryan's guest, Miss Davyss.
这位是--
This is a-
请稍等一下.
Wait just a minute.
隆格先生.
Mr. Long.
-幸会. -幸会.
- It's a pleasure to have you here. - Thank you.
-艾肯先生. -你好.
- Mr. Aiken. - How do you do?
你好.
How do you do?
加德纳先生.
Mr. Gardner.
-幸会. -幸会.
- Nice having you here. - Thank you.
-科斯先生. - 很高兴认识你. -你好.
- And Mr. Cross. - Very happy to know you.
请用晚餐,先生.
Dinner is served, sir.
谢谢.
Thank you.
请坐这个位置.
Will you take my place at the head of the table?
拉斯悌在科雷吉多尔岛上的医院里时, 是迪邬斯小姐在照料他.
Miss Davyss took care of Rusty when he was in the hospital at Corregidor.
她隶属于巴丹半岛的野战医院.
She's now attached to the field hospital at Bataan peninsula.
在巴丹半岛这还有护士?
There are nurses over here on Bataan?
有一些吧.
A few.
为什么其他的姑娘没来,...
Wasn't it mean enough for you in Corregidor...
难道你在科雷吉多尔呆厌了?
...without sending you girls over here?
嗯,是我要求的.
Well, I asked for it.
在这,我偶尔可以和拉斯悌通电话.
Over here, I can talk to Rusty sometimes on the phone.
多亏乔治,我们现在是邻居了.
By George, we're neighbors now!
下次把其他姑娘也带来,我们举行个舞会.
Next time, bring the other girls. We'll have a dance!
好主意!
Be a good idea!
真开心.
This is a lovely party.
非常棒.
It's swell.
谢谢.
Thanks.
-班尼. -是,长官.
- Benny. - Yes, sir.
谢谢.
Thank you.
汤.
Soup.
热的.
Hot.
烤饼,味道很好的.
Biscuits, very good.
谢谢.
Thank you.
真正的果酱,长官.-
Real jam, sir.
汤,烤饼,果酱.
Soup, biscuits, jam.
我还是要说一遍,一流的晚会.
I still say it's a swell party.
就差乐队和夜总会表演了.
Now all we need is an orchestra and a floor show.
迪邬斯,你将迎来人生最大的惊喜.
Miss Davyss, you're in for the biggest surprise of your life.
亲爱的女士
Dear old girl
知更鸟在..
The robin...
在你头顶歌唱,
...sings above you
亲爱的女士,
Dear old girl
它唱出的是我的爱意,
It speaks of how I love you
我思念着失去的爱人
The blinding tears are falling
泪流满面,
As I think of my lost pearl
我破碎的心在呼唤
And my broken heart is calling
呼唤着你的名字
Calling for you
亲爱的女士
Dear old girl
天哪,太美妙了.
Terrific! Wonderful!
呃,能允许我说几句吗?
If you'll excuse me, I have a lot of checking to do.
请.
Surely.
非常感谢你能过来.
Thank you very much for coming over.
这对我们很有意义.
It meant a great deal to all of us.
晚安,桑蒂.
Good night, Sandy.
晚安.
Good night.
-我也走了.能叫你桑蒂吗? -当然可以.
- Me too. Could I call you Sandy? - Sure.
-好的,晚安. -晚安.
- Well, good night. - Good night.
谢谢.
Thanks.
-晚安,桑蒂. -晚安.
- Good night, Sandy. - Good night.
我从没这么开心过,
I don't know when I've had such a nice time.
别忘了,我们现在是邻居了.
And don't forget now, we're neighbors and everything.
晚安,拉斯悌.
Good night, Rusty.
晚餐怎么样?
How's the chow?
棒极了.
Great!
唉,孩子,如果能带你去亚利桑那号,
Boy, if I had you on the old Arizona...
我可以做一个烤盘,把你头发弄卷.
...I'd make a pot roast that'd make your hair curl.
你哭了?
Crying?
我没哭.
I'm not crying.
只是他们这些人多好啊.
It's just that they're such nice guys.
你不是开玩笑吧.
You aren't kidding.
布里克雷先生和莱恩先生到了.
Mr. Brickley and Mr. Ryan.
这是机密.
Confidentially...
总统命令我,
...the President has ordered me...
以及部分重要人员转移到澳大利亚.
...and certain key personnel to Australia.
你们用快艇送我们去棉兰老岛.
Your boats will take us to Mindanao.
到那后,陆军航空队的轰炸机会送我们去南边.
From there, an Army bomber will fly us south.
你要我们把全部4艘艇都派出去吗?
You want to use all four of the boats?
全派出去,让他们准备好.
Yes. Get them ready.
这是机密.
This is secret.
重复一下,
Repeat.
是机密.
Secret.
出发日期决定后会通知你们.
You'll get the date when it's set.
是,长官.
Aye, aye, sir.
稍等一会.
Just a minute.
我想你们会需要这些海图的.
I think you'll find all the charts you'll need.
我想你们肯定也知道, 我们现在的处境不会好转.
You know it's not going well with us up here.
我们听到消息了,长官.
We get the news.
我们要把兵力集中起来,组建一个海军营.
We're scraping up all we can to form a naval battalion.
你能出几个人吗?
Can you spare any men?
我们可以出2个人,长官.
We have two extra crews, sir.
我用的着他们的,布里克雷.
I could use them, Brickley.
明白,长官.
Yes, sir.
我们向南走600英里.
We're going to run south 600 miles.
那天气很恶劣.
There's bad weather out there.
路上会很艰苦.
It'll be rough going.
如果有船发生故障, 我们也只能扔下他们不管.
If any boat breaks down, we'll have to let her go.
你们知道,只能牺牲他们了.
Expendable. You know what that means.
头天晚上去...
First night's run...
库约岛.
...Cuyo Islands.
白天我们要藏起来.
Hole up there during the day.
第二天晚上去...
Second night's run...
棉兰老岛的卡加延.
...to Cagayan on Mindanao.
那的机场还在我们手里, 但日本人推进很快.
We still hold the airfield there, but the Japs are moving fast.
不知道机场还能守多久.
It's a question of how long we can hang onto it.
靠近陆地时要保持百倍警惕.
Approach every landfall with caution.
时刻做好战斗或撤退准备.
Be prepared to fight or run for it.
但要记住,你们的首要任务是把这些人送出去.
But remember, your primary duty is to get these people out.
拉斯悌带将军上34号艇.
Rusty will take the admiral on the 34 boat.
我呢,带..
And I'll take...
陆军的人.
...the Army personnel with me.
晚上21:00出发.
We'll shove off at 2100.
汽艇准备好了吗?
Motor whaleboat ready?
随时可以出发,长官.
Whenever you are, sir.
莫加西能代我指挥一下吗?
Could Mulcahey take over my duty?
我想去看看安迪.
I'd like to go along and see Andy.
呃,好吧.我们21:00出发.
Yeah, sure. We'll shove off at 2100.
轻点,把板子抬起来.
Easy does it. Bring those boards up.
这些油桶将在到达第一任务点时丢弃.
These drums will go overboard on the first sea we hit.
交叉绑牢.
Cross lash them.
把它们放好放稳.
Put them on right and tight.
我刚才正跟他们这么说呢.
That's exactly what I've been telling them.
现在按船长和我说的去做.
Let's do it how the captain and I want it done.
长官,我们把能带的都带上了.
We can take all we got, sir.
安德鲁斯先生怎么样了?
How's Mr. Andrews?
医生说他过八九天就康复.
Doctor says he's good for about eight or nine days.
你代我向他告别.
Will you give him an aloha for me?
就2分钟
Just for two minutes.
尽量装得高兴点吧
Be cheerful and, you know, give him the old one-two-three.
好的.
Yes, ma'am.
海,布里克.
Hi, Brick.
你好啊...
Hello...
..伙计.
...fellas.
-嗨,安迪. -嗨,伙计.
- Hi, Andy. - Hi, fella.
感觉怎样?
How are you feeling?
这是咋了?
What is this?
鱼雷艇聚会吗?
A PT boat convention?
见到你真高兴.
It's good to see you.
你看起来不错,安迪.
You look swell, Andy.
你打算什么时候归队?
When will you quit stalling and get back to work?
很快.
Any day now.
这饭店伙食如何啊?
How's the chow in this hotel?
棒极了.
Wonderful.
鸽肉,
Squab.
猪排.
Steak.
-莫加西和马汉问你好. -还有厨子师.
- Mulcahey and Mahan say hello. - Cookie too.
所有的人.
The whole gang.
-34号艇怎样? -很好.
- How's the 34 boat? - Fine.
我想...
I suppose...
斯奈克正手忙脚乱的接手我的工作呢.
...Snake's been botching up my job.
他不是安德鲁斯.
He's no Andrews.
嗯,我这有些香烟.
Say, I got some cigarettes here.
来,抽几根.
Go on, have some.
不了.
Thanks.
我们正把他带上正轨,
We're keeping him in condition.
-他正努力夺你的位置. -努力就对了.
- He's trying to take your place. - Trying to is right.
我们准备好了一次任务.
We got a patrol to get ready for.
只要你复员,就有你的份.
The job's yours anytime you can make it.
-谢谢. -下周再见.
- Thanks. - See you next week.
- 再见. -别急.
- So long. - Take it easy.
头,我有话要说.
Say, Skipper-
请坐下,布里克.
Sit down, Brick.
你们接受的任务很棒.
That was a nice act you boys put on.
你从那知道的.
How did you get the word?
小道消息.
Scuttlebutt.
-嘿,布里克. -呃,我来拿.
Here. I'll get it for you.
如果你能活着,
If you get through...
帮我把这些寄出去,行吗?
...mail these, will you?
好的,我答应你.
Sure, if there's any mail.
这封给我妈的.
One to Mother.
这封给迈拉.
One to Myra.
你知道的,她在洛克西德.
You know, she's at Lockheed.
我还写好了遗嘱.
I wrote out a will too.
你倒是都给自己安排好了.
That was a pretty good act you put on yourself.
你还有什么没做好的事情...
Any unfinished business that you want me...
要我帮你完成吗?
...to take care of for you?
或要我向你家人转达什么特别的话...
Anything particular you'd like to have me say to your folks...
或带给迈拉?
...or to Myra?
我都写在信里了.
I guess I've written about all I had to say.
很抱歉,我不能为中队做更多事情.
Sorry I couldn't do more for the squadron.
有人吗?
Is there anybody on duty there?
给我接野战医院.
Give me the field hospital.
我是海军中尉莱恩.
This is Lt. Ryan speaking, Navy.
请叫护士迪邬斯少尉接电话.
I want to talk to one of your nurses. Lieutenant Davyss.
桑蒂·迪邬斯.
Sandy Davyss.
我不知道她名字.
I don't know her first name.
只知道她叫桑蒂·迪邬斯.
Sandy. Sandy Davyss.
－喂,.. －呸,再喂也没用,.
Oh, what's the use?
嗨,别着急.
Here! Take it easy!
你还有的是时间.
You've got plenty of time.
再试试嘛.
Ik eep trying.
-把信号板拿来. -是,长官.
- Bring that sign. - Yes, sir.
-立--正! -稍--息.
At ease.
你们大家都是好样的.
You're a swell bunch.
很荣幸曾与你们共事.
I'm glad to have been able to serve with you.
我本可以告诉你们...
I'd like to be able to tell you...
说我们这次出动是去求援的.
...that we were going out to bring back help.
但那不是实情.
But that wouldn't be the truth.
我们要放弃这的防线去执行特别任务.
We're going down the line to do a job.
而你们则要到巴丹去,加入陆军作战.
You're going to Bataan with the Army.
你们本来是海军,
That isn't what you've been trained for.
但是现在陆军需要你们.
But they need your help.
你们这些...
You older men...
老兵...
...with longer service records...
要照顾好新兵.
...take care of the kids.
或许...
Maybe...
就说这么多吧.
That's all.
愿上帝保佑你们.
God bless you.
-我是莱恩. -你好,拉斯悌. -你好,桑蒂.
- Ryan speaking. - Hello, Rusty.
15号来找你方便吗?
Is the 15th all right with you?
不行,桑蒂.
No, it isn't, Sandy.
那16号行吗?
Would the 16th be better?
哪天都不行.
Nothing would be better.
喂,到底怎么了?
Well, what is this, anyway?
我想我们该说再见了.
I guess it's goodbye.
能告诉我你要去哪吗?
Can you tell me where you're going?
不行.
I wish I could.
你还回来吗?
Are you coming back?
我也不知道.
I'm not sure.
但我想是不会回来了.
But I don't think so.
呃...那么,这次是真的再见了?
Well, this is really goodbye, then.
曾经一切都那么美好,对吗?
It's been awfully nice, hasn't it?
曾经那么美好.
It's been swell.
桑蒂,你知道,我不会说话.
Look, Sandy, I'm no good at talk.
我已经给你写了封信,你很快就会收到.
I've written you a letter. Shorty Long will get it to you.
对不起小姐,我们得把它带走了. 我们要向南方转移.
Sorry, miss. We got to take this out. We're moving south.
总机?
Operator?
你怎么把我们挂断了?
You've cut us off.
有将军要线路?不能等我们讲完吗?
A couple of generals? Couldn't they wait till we were through?
汽艇来了,长官.
Motor whaleboat coming alongside, sir.
再接迪邬斯小姐.
Put Miss Davyss back on the line.
总机,线路怎么了?
Operator, what's gone wrong with this line?
断了.
Gone dead.
很麻烦,长官.
That's tough, sir.
希望那什么将军确实在说重要的事.
Hope what those generals had to say was important.
-再见,医生. -再见,长官.
- So long, Doc. - Goodbye, sir.
再见,威尔.
So long, Willie.
-好好干. -是,长官.
- Be a good kid. - Yes, sir.
-再见,斯利姆. -再见.
- So long, Slim. - So long.
-祝你平安,萨米. -也祝你平安,宝贝.
- Shalom aleichem, Sammy. - Same to you, baby.
-再见,菲尔. -你们现在是陆军了.
- So long, Phil, old boy. - You're in the Army now.
-准备好了,布里克雷. -长官,准备就绪.
- Ready, Brickley. - Ready, sir.
长官,请在我帽子上签个名.
Sir, please autograph my hat.
嗯,当然可以.
Why, certainly.
-晚上好,长官.
Good evening, sir.
好了,莱恩.
Ready, Ryan.
收缆.
Wind them up.
走吧,晦气. 快走!
Come on, Bad Luck. Scat!
列队!
Fall in!
向右转!
Right face!
原地踏步!
Ground step!
齐--步...
Forward.
走!
March!
很准时.
On time.
只来了3艘.
Only three boats.
一定是损失了一艘
Must have lost one.
什么命令,长官.
Orders, sir?
-中队留下来归马丁将军指挥. -是,长官.
The squadron will work down here under General Martin.
我们在巴丹还有几个人, 我打算去把他们接来.
We've got quite a few men at Bataan. I'd like to go pick them up.
-你在那已经尽力了. -明白了,长官.
You've done all you can up there.
航空汽油呢?-
What about aviation gasoline?
我们会设法弄来的.
We'll try to find what you need.
那鱼雷呢?
What about torpedoes?
在Cebu可能还有点,我去查一下.
There may be some at Cebu. I'll inquire.
我们一定得弄到航空汽油和鱼雷才行.
We've got to have aviation gas and torpedoes.
我明白.
I realize that.
我们会把敌军的动静通知你们的.
We'll keep you informed as to enemy activity.
关于打击日本舰队的这个问题, 你们可以自行出击.
Plan your own operations against their ships.
但每天都要向我报告你们的活动.
But report to me daily by phone.
-再见,布里克雷. -再见,长官.
- Goodbye, Brickley. - Goodbye, sir.
莱恩.
Ryan.
再见,长官.
Goodbye, sir.
真是倒霉透顶,怎么弄的?
That's tough luck. What happened?
机油失效,所有轴承都烧毁了.
Oil failure. Burnt out every cock-eyed bearing.
宿务那有船坞,我们拖你们去.
There's a shipyard at Cebu. We'll tow you.
-最好把发动机拆了. -我已经在拆了.
- Better tear down those engines. - I've already started.
谢谢你们拖我们去那.
Thanks for the tow.
不用谢.
Por nada.
我会报答你的.
Do the same for you someday.
我可不希望那种事落到我头上.
I hope not.
想想那些32号艇的家伙.
Wonder about the kids on the 32 boat.
-早上3点那会还在我们正横位置.
They were abeam of us at 3:00 in the morning.
然后就不见了.
Then we missed them.
-不会是被巡洋舰击中了吧?
Suppose that cruiser got them?
别操心了,布里克.
Stop worrying, Brick.
他们会出现的.
They'll show up.
我要去机场.
I'm going over to the airfield.
搭架联络机去找找他们.
Pick up an old crate, see if I can find them.
你代我指挥,嗯?
Take over, will you?
-别着急. -检查一下支板.
- Take it easy. - Have a look at that plank.
当心珊瑚.
And watch out for the coral.
能注意听一下吗,大家注意.
Can I have your attention? Attention, all hands.
布里克雷先生要我宣读这个声明:
Mr. Brickley has requested that I make the following announcement:
中队的全体军官及士兵...
For every officer and man in this squadron...
由于你们在当前这张战争中表现出的勇气
...for your work in the war to date-
哈皮,去那帮他一把.
Happy, get in there and give him a hand.
将军...
The General...
授予你们...
...has awarded the Silver Star...
银星奖章.
...for gallantry.
祖尼,过去帮他.
Junior, get in and help him.
支板松了,底下全是珊瑚.
Planking's loose. The bottom's full of coral.
这下可好了.
All right.
好消息.
Got a little news.
中队的全体军官和士兵..
To every officer and man in this squadron...
由于你们在战争中的表现...
...for your work in the war to date-
对不起,长官.
Excuse me, sir.
这只黑猫这段时间一直呆在这艘艇上.
All this time, this black cat has been aboard this boat.
将军授予银星奖章以表彰你们展现出的勇气.
The General has awarded the Silver Star for gallantry.
顺便说下,这只猫本该在32号艇的.
By rights, the cat ought to have been aboard the 32 boat.
也许是它给我们41号艇带来了好运.
Maybe this black cat is good luck for us, the 41 boat.
你们听到没,你们被授予银猫奖章.
Anyway, you've been awarded the Silver Cat.
找到他们了吗?
Any luck?
什么也没发现.
Not a sign of them.
糟了.
Fire in the paint locker.
好了,马汉,怎么会这样?
All right, Mahan. Think fast. What happened?
都怪我,长官.
It's all my fault, sir.
我跟莫加西说...
You see, I says to Mulcahey...
"我们给大伙弄点啤酒来吧"
..."Let's get the crews a couple of beers. "
是我听到过的最蠢的理由.
That's the dumbest excuse I ever heard.
-对不起.
- I'm sorry. - That helps!
当我们醒过来,它就成这模样了.
So when we gets back, she was high and dry.
发动机启动不了了.都是我的错.
The engines wouldn't start. It's just as much my fault.
闭嘴.我的事我自己来扛.
Pipe down. I'll take the rap.
见鬼去吧,我要把你们两个都降为二等兵.
For two cents, I'd bust you both to seaman second.
都是你多嘴.
Ik eep your mouth out of my business.
舵轮,支柱和轴全都坏了,长官.
Everything, sir. Wheels, struts and shafts.
-是我的错. -怎么发生的?
- It's my fault. - How'd it happen?
-不能怪别人. -到底怎么发生的?
- There's no one else to blame. - How did it happen?
是这样的.
It's like this.
我们又热又累又渴.
We were hot, tired and thirsty.
我和施拉格就喝了点啤酒...
Slug and I thought we'd get some beer-
在41号艇待命,把它拖走检查损伤情况.
Stand by with the 41 boat. We'll pull her off and see the damage.
-是,长官.但我不想... -啤酒怎么样?
- Yes, sir, but I don't want- - How was the beer?
我们一点都没喝.
We didn't have any.
35号艇已准备好.
Ready on the 35 boat.
Ready on the 35 boat!
重复命令.
Repeat the instructions.
如果受到攻击,就将艇烧毁, 我们会来搭救你们的.
If you're attacked, burn your boats. We'll try and pick you up.
如果受到攻击,
If we're attacked...
将艇烧毁...
...burn your boats.
我们来搭救你们.
And we'll try to pick you up.
乔斯,费尔南德斯·玛丽亚!
Jos?Fernandez Maria!
到那边去.
Get going there.
你们都给我好好干活!
I'll whop you with a neck yoke.
喂,布里克!
Brick!
左舷支柱和轴弯了.
Got a bent strut and shaft on the port side.
- 你检查了压板了吗? - 压板没事.
- You check your planking? - Planking's okay.
老爹,你认为要多久能修好?
How long you figure it will take, Dad?
还不清楚.
Can't tell yet.
我可不会不顾质量的赶工.
I won't knock off till I'm done.
我该怎么报答你呢?
How am I going to pay you?
去狠狠教训小日本,这就足够了.
You'll fight them and I'll fix them. That's pay enough.
我只关心能在小日本打到这来之前修好它.
Only hope we get them out of here before the Japs move in.
你认为他们离这还有多远?
How far away you figure they are?
就在附近岛屿那.
Half the nearby islands.
近来小日本的巡洋舰和驱逐舰成天吵个不停.
Cruisers and destroyers have been nosing around for days.
如果他们登陆了,你打算怎么办?
What are you going to do if they make a landing?
我要跟他们决一死战.
They'll have to fight to get me.
你,埃斯沃多·佩雷拉!
You, Ascevedo Perreira!
离水桶远点.
Get away from that water bucket.
没到时间呢.
Drink on your own time.
哈,我想起来了,来吸一口吧?
That reminds me. How about a little snort?
晚点再说吧.
Later.
船长!
Captain.
潜艇.
Submarine.
S-29潜艇来了,长官.
S-29 coming up the channel, sir.
食品准备好了.
And chow is ready.
我奉命前来装载粮食和奎宁...
I have orders to load food and quinine...
运往科雷吉多尔岛.
...and try to run it to Corregidor.
总部还希望能利用汽船穿越封锁输送补给.
They also want the interisland steamers to try the blockade.
我们这有7条小汽轮.
We've got seven small steamers here.
另外还可以再装配出一两条明轮船.
We might rig up a side-wheeler or two.
还有一些汽艇.
And some motored sailors.
我立刻安排补给品的事情.
I'll arrange for supplies at once.
咱们快点吧.
Let's give her a whirl.
我还有事,再见.
I've got work to do. See you later.
等等,斯纳菲.
Oh, Snuffy.
能给我们几条鱼雷吗?
How about getting torpedoes from you?
给你那些爆竹用?
For those cracker boxes of yours?
我自己都不知道什么时候才能再得到补充呢.
No telling when we'll see a mother ship again.
你们巡逻多久了?
How long you been on patrol?
战争爆发时就开始了.
Since the war started.
那你们都有什么战果呢?
What did you get?
两艘小型护卫舰.
Two small freighters.
没办法,运气太差.
We had hard luck.
你们在海底转悠时,这些破烂 爆竹已经击沉了2艘巡洋舰...
While you've been cruising, those cracker boxes have sunk 2 cruisers...
一艘轻型航空母舰...
...an auxiliary aircraft carrier...
一艘1万吨的油船和一艘大型护卫舰..
...a 10,000-ton tanker, a large freighter...
以及不计其数的小日本兔崽子...
...a flock of barges and numerous sons of Nippon.
还有我们的正事....
And also in our brief career...
我们传送了比西联还要多的的信息.
...we've carried more messages than Western Union.
我很想帮你们,但我有命令..
I'd like to help you out, but I got orders-
[台词如此，1932年奥斯卡奖名单并未见此片]
1932年奥斯卡获奖电影"德伯家的苔丝"
Who played the leading lady in "Tess of the d'Urbevilles"...
谁演的女主角?
...in 1932 at the Academy?
你的艇员知道吗?
And does your crew know about it?
你们想要多少?
How many do you want?
你有16条鱼雷.
You've got 16.
给我们8条.
We'll take 8.
我们会把它们送到它们该去的地方的.
And we'll try and put them where they belong.
好吧.
Thanks.
请让一下.
Do you mind?
我有好消息给你.
I finally have good news for you.
明天会有轰炸机从澳大利亚飞来...
Tomorrow, bombers will take off from Australia...
轰炸这的日本舰队.
...and blast every Jap ship here.
我们一直盼着呢.
We've been hoping for that.
但还有一个问题.
But there's a catch in it.
有艘巡洋舰正向这驶来.
A cruiser is headed this way.
可能还有驱逐舰跟着.
Probably has destroyers with her.
情报显示那是"最上"级重巡洋舰.
Information says she's of the Mogami class.
明白那对你们意味着什么吗?
Does that mean anything to you?
十分清楚,长官.
That's about as big as they come. Yes, sir.
除非你们去阻止他们,否则..
She'll shell these food ships before they get away from the dock.
我们的运送粮食的船队还没离港就会被消灭.
Unless you boys can stop her.
你们能办到吗?
Can do?
-我们试试.长官. -很好.
- Can try, sir. - That's fair enough.
赶快去准备吧,用我的车子.祝你们好运.
Better get going. Take my driver and good luck.
我来开车.
I'll drive.
"最上"级巡洋舰,什么感想,莱恩?
Mogami-class cruiser mean anything to you, Mr. Ryan?
-什么情况,头? -有什么消息,布里克?
- What's up, Skipper? - Any news, Brick?
老爹,还要多久能修好?
How soon can you get them ready?
不超过3天.
Not for three days, with the 35 boat.
- 还得加快进度. -那些轴承很费时间的
- You can go quicker than that. - Them bearings take time!
拉斯悌的艇好了,但是艇身需要先泡24小时.
Rusty's boat's ready, but her hull ought to soak 24 hours.
那...41号艇只好单独出击了.
The 41 boat will have to go alone, then.
把41号艇准备好.
Get her ready.
好的,小伙子们,来吧.
All right, gang, let's go.
莱恩先生,这太过分了.
This has gone far enough.
为什么好事总被41号艇抢了?
That 41 boat is always hogging the good jobs.
浸泡艇身这事,我们可以在路上完成啊.
We'll soak on our way to hit the Japs.
我们干啥?坐这干等他们回来?
What do we do? Sit on our duffs until they get back?
单凭41号艇很难完成任务的.
The 41 can't handle this job alone.
怎么样,长官?
How about it, sir?
好吧.可是,万一它开始进水的话...
But if she starts taking water...
...必须立即返航.
...turn back.
准备完毕.
Ready here.
埃斯佩朗莎,它下水了.
There she goes, Esperanzo.
就像水过猫背般滑顺.
Like water off a cat's back.
嘿,拉斯悌!
Rusty!
我不喝酒的,但我要痛饮庆祝.
I ain't a drinking man.
不过我会把大部分留到你们回来再喝的.
But I'm saving most of this till you get back.
在那!乖乖,它在那!
There she is! Jumping Jeremiah, there she is!
拉斯悌注意了.
Rusty from Brick.
我从滩头那边发起攻击,你从海上进攻.
I'll make my run from the beach. You make yours from seaward.
完毕.
Over.
我是拉斯悌.
Brick from Rusty.
收到命令.
Wilco.
预备!
Stand by.
一号发射!
Fire one!
二号发射!
Fire two!
拉斯悌准备.
Rusty from Brick.
开始攻击.
Start your run.
开始攻击,完毕.
Start your run. Over.
我是拉斯悌,收到.
Brick from Rusty. Wilco.
出击!
Here we go!
预备!
Stand by!
一号发射!
Fire one!
二号发射!
Fire two!
准备好鱼雷!
Stand by your torpedoes!
-就绪. -3号发射!
- One! - Fire three!
-4号发射!
Fire four!
鱼雷准备!
Stand by torpedoes!
来点漂亮的!
Let's make these good!
准备.
Yards.
3号发射!
Fire three!
4号发射!
Fire four!
我们走!
Let's drag our tails out of here!
他们看不到我们长官,这岛挡着呢.
We're lee of the land, sir. They've lost us.
你来.
Take over.
布里克他们应该有机会跑掉的,是吧长官?
Think Mr. Brickley had a chance to get away, sir?
他总能跑掉的.
He usually does.
机枪要没弹药了.
Running low on 50-caliber!
-火势失去控制了! -抓住马汉!
- We can't control the fire! - Grab Mahan!
隐蔽!
Take cover!
比分多少?
What's the score?
刚第一局,孩子.
Ninth inning, kid.
抱歉,神父不在.
I'm sorry. The father is not here, sir.
他在医院呆了2天了.
He has been at the hospital for two days.
军人死后应当有葬礼.
A serviceman is supposed to have a funeral.
这是对他为国捐躯的一种肯定.
That's a tribute to the way he spent his life.
抬棺...
Escort...
鸣枪....
...firing squad...
身覆国旗...
...wrapped in the flag he served under...
他应享有的.
...and died for.
但战争时期,只能舍弃这些奢望...
In war you got to forget those things...
按我们能够办到的最好的方式下葬.
...and get buried the best way you can.
你们都知道...
You all knew...
德国佬拉森,还有施拉格 马汉.
...Squarehead Larsen and Slug Mahan.
他们是一对好水兵.
They were just a couple of bluejackets who did their job.
尽职尽责.
Did it well.
34号艇不能没有他们.
34 boat couldn't have got along without them.
德国佬 拉森.
Squarehead Larsen.
他是海军最好的厨师.
He's the best cook in the Navy.
他最爱亚力桑那号.
He loved the old Arizona.
现在他们都去了.
Now they're both gone.
施拉格....
Slug...
他总是...
...he was always...
...吟诗
...quoting verse.
...弄曲.
Bits of poetry.
嗯...所以
So...
现在给他献上一首诗.
...here's one for him.
我唯一熟悉的一首.
It's about the only one I know.
在广阔的...
Under the wide...
星空之下
...starry sky
掘好墓穴
Dig the grave
让我安眠.
And let me lie.
开心的活着
Glad did I live
无悔的逝去
And gladly die
我只有一个愿望
And I laid me down with a will
你们在我的墓碑上刻下:
This be the verse you grave for me
他安眠在他长久向往的地方
Here he lies where he longed to be
大海...
Home is the sailor...
她是水手的家
...home from the sea
就如山岗是猎人的家.
And the hunter home from the hill.
可以吗,长官?
Is it all right, sir?
嗯.
Sure.
谢谢你,孩子.
Thank you, son.
对不起.酒吧关闭了.
Sorry. Bar closed.
- 我们要走了! -不,酒吧没关门.
- We go away! - Sorry, bar is open.
不,不!日本人来了,日本人就要打来了!
No, no! Jap come, Jap come!
音乐!
Musica, Se駉r Teniente.
音乐.Es 圣·弗朗西斯科
Musica. Es San Francisco.
这是WBKR 圣·弗朗西斯科.
WBKR San Francisco.
打断一下.
A brief interruption, please.
下面播报来自菲律宾的不幸消息.
This is spot and tragic news from the Philippines.
经过艰苦血战之后...
The white flag of surrender was hoisted...
今天下午巴丹堡垒升起了白旗.
...on the bloody heights of Bataan this afternoon.
3万6千名美国士兵...
36,000 United States soldiers...
他们饥渴疲惫...
...hungry...
衣衫褴褛....
...ragged, half-starved shadows...
身陷绝境拼死奋战...
...trapped like rats but dying like men...
终被2万日军精锐部队击败.
...were finally worn down by 200,000 picked Japanese troops.
他们为不可动摇的信念战斗...
Men who fight for an unshakable faith...
超乎常人.
...are more than flesh.
然而他们毕竟是血肉之躯,
But they're not steel.
生命终会凋零.
Flesh must yield at last.
承受超过极限时,
Endurance melts away.
结局就不可避免.
The end must come.
巴丹虽然沦陷了.
Bataan has fallen.
但是巴丹守军那激励了...
But the spirit that made it a beacon...
所有爱好自由的人民的精神永远不会消退.
...to all lovers of liberty will never falter.
在日军猛烈炮击科雷吉多尔...
The white flag was hardly hoisted over Bataan...
我们在菲律宾最后的据点后,
...before Jap artillery began slamming away at Corregidor...
巴丹半岛终于升起了白旗.
...our last strong point in the Philippines.
伙计们,布里克雷牺牲了...
Men, with Mr. Brickley gone...
我将继续做他会做的事.
...I'll carry on the way I think he would.
我同意你关于莱特岛的观点.
I think you're right about Leyte Island.
那边有陆军的人.或许我们能坚守到援军到来.
There's Army men over there. Maybe we can hold out till help comes.
全力守住每一个桥头和隘口,拉弗悌.
Dig in at every bridgehead and pass, Lefty.
让小日本崽子付出代价.
Make them pay.
-祝你们好运. -再见.
- Good luck, fellas. - So long.
重复命令.
Repeat your orders.
找到马丁将军,向他报告并保护他.
To find and report to General Martin and keep him up to date.
好了,出发吧.
All right, get going.
-嗨,你好.小伙子. -你好,长官.
- Old Franklin High, Junior. - Roosevelt High, sir.
老爹,我要去找布里克.
Dad, I'm going to try and find Brick.
你为什么不跟我们一起走呢?
Why don't you come along with me?
我在这干了40年了,孩子.
I've worked 40 years for this, son.
我就是死也要战死在这.
If I leave it, they'll have to carry me out.
嗨,小伙子.
Hello, kid.
我们都以为日本人打中你们了.
We thought the Japs got you.
我们也一位他们打中你们了.
I thought they got you too.
发生什么事了?
What happened?
我们往南走的时候搁浅了.
Ran south through shallow water.
你的人呢?
Where's your crew?
马汉 和拉森牺牲了.
We lost Mahan and Larsen.
-还有几个受了伤. -他们怎么打中施拉格的?
- Couple of the kids got hurt. - How'd they get Slug?
飞机上的机枪打的.
Machine gun from a plane.
真不幸.
That's great.
很高兴您回来.
Glad to see you back.
你的船呢?
Where's your boat?
被日本飞机的炸弹击中.
Jap bombers got her.
我们把船烧了.
We burned the 35 boat.
艇员往莱特岛去了
The gang headed for Leyte.
它闯过来了.
She's through.
马丁将军把她转给了陆军...
General Martin turned her over to the Army...
去拉瑙湖执行任务.
...to run errands on Lake Lanao.
好了,海军兄弟.我们接管了.
Okay, Navy. We're taking over.
好吧,陆军们,把她带走吧.
Okay, Army. Take her away.
好了,鼓起劲,我们要出发了.
All right, gather up your gear. We're heading out.
-你也在找亚利桑那号吗? -没错.
You looking for the Arizona too?
布里克雷.
Brickley.
-我受命载你和莱恩先生飞去澳大利亚. -澳大利亚?
I have orders to fly you and Ryan to Australia.
对,还有准尉加德纳和克洛斯.
Also ensigns Gardner and Cross.
-他们在镇西面. -我们会找到他们.
- They're west of town. - We'll find them.
为什么要我们去?我们只是上尉而已.
Why us? We're just a couple of lieutenants.
你们证明了PT快艇在战争中的价值.
You men have proved that PT boats have some value in this war.
华府希望你们能参与建设这支部队.
Washington wants you in the States to build them up.
这是命令.
Those are my orders.
这些人呢?
And the men?
没地方了.
There isn't room.
-可是马丁将军,这些人... -飞机上没有地方了,布里克雷.
- General Martin, those men- - There isn't room for them.
-桥准备好了,长官. -炸吧.
- Bridge ready, sir. - Let her go.
我认为我们犯了个错误..
I think we're making a mistake-
飞机上没位置了!布里克雷. 即刻去机场报到.
There isn't room. Report to the airport right away.
开车. 你最好赶紧去.
Driver. And you better get going.
事情总不能如我们所愿
Makes a fine pair of heels out of us.
我和莱恩先生接到命令要撤回国内.
Mr. Ryan and I have been ordered out.
祝你们好运,长官.
Good luck, sir.
也祝你好运,钟斯.
Good luck to you, Jonesy.
也祝你好运.
That goes for you too.
照顾好他.
Watch him.
长官,我想和你握个手.
I'd like to shake your hand.
很荣幸.
That'll be a pleasure.
纵有千言万语,我只想说...
The book doesn't mean much out here, so I'm going to say...
你一直都很优秀....再见,布里克雷.
...so long, Brick. You've been a swell guy.
再见,艾瑞斯.
So long, Irish.
再见,拉斯悌>
So long, Rusty.
再见,迈克尔.
So long, you big mick.
帆缆军士长的助手莫加西.
Chief Boatswain's Mate Mulcahey.
-你接替指挥. -是,长官.
Take over.
向--右--转!
Right face!
交叉步,跟我来!
Cross step. Follow me!
-第四陆战旅. -41号.
- Fourth Marines. - Forty-one.
谢谢.
Thank you, sir.
- 斯仲格中尉. - 39号.
- Lieutenant Strong. - Thirty-nine.
好的.
Fine.
- 给. - 谢谢,长官.
- Here you are. - Thank you, sir.
布里克雷,美国海军.
Brickley, U.S.N.
27号.
Number 27.
莱恩,美国海军.
Ryan, U.S.N.
28号.
Number 28.
对不起,我不知道上面有没有我的名字.
I'm sorry. I don't know if my name's on that list.
我是詹姆斯·莫顿少校.
Morton. Major James Morton.
31号,上校.
You're number 31, Major.
我能走吗?
I get to go?
每架飞机搭30个人.
Each plane holds 30 men.
如果来两架,您就能走.
If two planes come, you'll get to go.
31号,谢谢.
31. Thank you.
真希望那些人会出现.
Wish those kids would show up.
##哎,Ohio!
Ohio!
嗨,拉斯悌,你好吗?
Hi, Rusty. How are you, fella?
你什么时候离开科雷吉多尔的?
When did you leave The Rock?
四五天前,或者有一周了吧.我也记不清了.
Four or five days ago, a week. I don't know.
还记得桑蒂吗?那个蓝眼睛的小护士.
Remember Sandy, the little nurse with the green eyes?
-记得. -其他11,000人也记得.
Sure. So will 11,000 other guys.
你知道她现在在哪吗?
You know where she is?
不,我不知道.
No, I don't know where she'd be now.
她可能逃出来在山里...
She might be out in the hills...
或者在某个监狱里.
...or a prisoner somewhere.
刷洗碟子.
Swell dish.
我猜她对你要比对其他人重要的多.
I guess she meant more to you than she did the rest of us.
我真的希望她没事.
I sure hope she's okay.
我最后一次和她说话..
Last time I talked to her...
是在巴丹的电话里.
...was over the telephone on Bataan.
声音还是那么动听.
Voice sounded swell.
那么清晰...
Clear...
..勇敢...
...and brave...
那么遥远.
...and far away.
只有一架飞机.
Only one plane.
加德纳和克洛斯到底去哪了呢?
Where do you suppose Gardner and Cross could have gotten to?
可以上人了,上尉.
Quite a load, Captain.
-嗨,斯莫基! -嗨,乔.
- Hey, Smokey! - Hey, Joe.
喊到名字的,请登机.
As I call your names, kindly step into the plane.
1号,T.V.史密斯中士.
Number one, Sergeant T.V. Smith.
2号,A.C.詹姆斯中尉.
Number two, Lieutenant A. C. James.
立正!
Attention!
布里克雷.
Brickley.
见到将军时,告诉他这就要失陷了.
When you see the General, tell him the end here is near.
如果他问你我想要什么...
If he should ask you what we want...
告诉他,我想要一只海军特遣舰队...
...tell him a Navy task force...
满载汽油的油船和十万人.
...a tanker loaded with gasoline and 100,000 men.
有这些,我们就能收复失陷的岛屿.
Give me that, and we can start taking the islands back.
我知道他不可能得到这么多,但是 如果他问起来,你就这么跟他说.
I know he probably hasn't got them, but if he asks you, tell him.
是,长官.找到加德纳和克洛斯了吗?
Yes, sir. Have they located Gardner and Cross?
没有,还在找.
No, they're still looking for them.
27号,海军上尉布里克雷先生.
Number 27, Lieutenant Brickley, Navy.
28号,海军上尉莱恩先生.
Number 28, Lieutenant Ryan, Navy.
29号,加德纳准尉.
Number 29, Ensign Gardner.
30号,克洛斯准尉.
Number 30, Ensign Cross.
31号,詹姆斯·莫顿少校.
Thirty-one, Major James Morton.
到.
Here.
32号,卡特上尉.
Number 32, Captain Carter.
到.-
Here.
齐了.
That's all.
再见,中士.
So long, Sergeant.
莫顿少校,卡特上尉,很抱歉.
Major Morton and Captain Carter, I'm sorry.
你们的位置是留给那两人人的.
Your places are assigned to these two men. I'm sorry.
- 对不起我们迟到了,长官.我们遇到炮击. -我们的车子坏了
- Sorry we're late, but we got strafed. - We both lost our bikes.
- 实在抱歉,长官. - 没关系.
- I'm sorry, sir. - Not at all.
-祝你们好运,水兵. -祝你们一路顺风.
- Good luck, sailor. - I hope you have a smooth trip home.
如果你活着,能帮忙给我太太捎个口信吗?
If you get through, would you mail a note to my wife?
当然.
Of course.
这是她的电话,给她打个长途电话.
Here's her phone number. Call her long-distance.
告诉她你见过我,我永远爱她.
Tell her you saw me and that I still love her.
我一定会的.
You bet I will.
记住了,水兵.
Make no passes at her, sailor.
-一路顺风! -等等.
- Happy landings! - Wait a minute.
你自己给她打电话吧, 我在这还有点事.
You phone her. I got business here.
你要回国办你的事.让开.
You got business back in the States. Gangway.
你为谁战斗,布里克雷?
Who are you working for?
为你自己吗?
Yourself?
他说的对,兄弟.
He said it, fella.
谢谢.
Thanks.
不客气.
Not at all.
还有飞机来吗?
How many more planes are coming in?
不会再有了.
None.
孩子...
Look, son...
我们回国是有任务的.
...we're going home to do a job.
那就是--为打回来作好准备.
And that job is to get ready to come back.
-- 明白了吗? -- 明白.
Check?  Check